ISRAEL KINFU

Greenville, TX | (301)357-3622 | ikinfu@terpmail.umd.edu|linkedin.com/in/israelkinfu| https://github.com/isri12

Summary

Software developer with 2+ years of experiance seeking to leverage experience in software development and cloud computing.

Skills

Platforms /Languages: C/C++, Python, Linux

Software/Tools: bash scripting, Git, Container (Docker, Podman), CMake, QT GUI, MATLAB, LabVIEW, Visio,

Jira, CANoe/CANalyzer/CAPL Scripting.

Interests: AWS/Azure, Dev OPS, Cloud Computing, Jenkins, Ansible, Terraform, CI/CD Pipeline, Kubernetes.

Work Experience

Associate Software Engineer :L3 Harris Technologies, Greenville, TX

June 2022-Present

- Developed using C++/Python and took an active role in systems integration and core application development.
- Involved in a completed Software Development Life Cycle.
- Participate in the DevOps design, Development, Testing and release of new features.
- Led Unit testing and system level testing team for all phases of application development cycle.

Level 2 Electrical Systems Design and Analysis Engineer: Boeing, Oklahoma City, OK

Aug. 2019 - June 2022

- Supported Component and sub-system design analysis and trade- off studies .
- Performed environmental and system qualification tests to verify operational and functional requirements.
- Reviewed engineering designs and test plans to ensure they're free of potential hazards or safety risks.
- Managed Projects to meet performance, schedule and cost goals.

Software Engineer Co-Op: Harley-Davidson Motor Company, Wauwatosa, WI

Aug. 2017- Dec. 2018

Project Livewire Infotainment team - Harley Davidson's first production electric motorcycle

- Developed software requirements related to CAN network and troubleshoot component/system engineering parts/modules.
- Simulated a vehicle CAN network nodes using CANoe with CAPI scripting as well as with Matlab Simulink.
- Supported software/Hardware development and worked on UI and CAN diagnostics on the 2019 BoomBox GTS Infotainment.
- Optimized software requirements related to CAN network traffic for systems integration.

Embedded Engineer Intern: Juxtopia Llc, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD

May 2016- August 2016

- Worked on AR Goggles and Software systems with leading Professional Software and Hardware Engineers.
- Used Assembly and C/C++ to Debug and Trace ARM cortex-M processor.

Education

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

May 2019

B.S. Electrical Engineering

Technical/Engineering Projects

125 mile E-bike Challenge at UMD Department of Electrical Engineering College Park, MD

Feb.2019- DEC. 2019

- Leading a team of four to construct an e-bike that can run up to 125 mile a single charge.
- Integrated Current, voltage and speed sensor embedded with CAN BUS communication protocol and IOT.

Winner of 2018 Alumni Cup competition at UMD Department of Electrical Engineering College Park, MD

Feb.2018

Conversion normal bike to E-bike published on <u>Instructables</u> and <u>Github</u> Northrop Grumman IOT challenge

Dec. 2018 March 2017

Smart door lock system with three authentication systems (biometrics, RFID sensor, and Bluetooth) on raspberry pi.

Developed a camera that captures a user entering the door and upload the data with timestamp.

Tarps Racing Baja Electronics Team

August 2016- Feb.2019

- Collected RPM and engine performance data using Race capture module.
- Integrated GPS and 3G data into the system and captured driver impact data in real time.

Smart Mirror Project March 2016

- Established smooth face tracking on the mirror using Raspberry pi with OpenCV Application Programming Interface.
- Developed control system that displays calendar and weather with voice activation.